# Le Phong Vu

With nine years of experience, my expertise lies in building microservices using C++, Golang, or Ruby, as well as performing data engineering tasks such as building and monitoring data pipelines. I am seeking a challenging role where I can apply my technical skills and contribute to the development of innovative solutions in a collaborative environment.

139/32 Phan Dang Luu Ho Chi Minh City (84) 34-344-0247 lephongvu90@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Ascenda** — Backend Engineer

Dec 2021 - Present

Developing backend systems using Ruby Hanami and Rails, showcasing proficiency in object-oriented programming.

Designing and implementing an alert and monitoring system using Prometheus and Grafana, demonstrating experience in production systems design including High Availability, application performance, system, time-series, and dashboarding.

Optimizing database performance by analyzing query execution plans, identifying bottlenecks, and implementing efficient indexing strategies to improve overall system performance.

# CIC Data, Ho Chi Minh, Ha Noi— Backend, Data Engineer

June 2019 - Nov 2021

Collaborating with cross-functional teams, I have utilized my expertise in Golang and backend development to design and optimize high-performance backend services. Leveraging the power of Golang, I have developed scalable and efficient solutions that enable seamless communication and integration between different components of the system. Develop CLI tool for internal team.

Architecting and managing a robust data pipeline with over 500 TB of data using Hadoop, Spark, Airflow, and Grafana.

Collaborating with cross-functional teams to develop and optimize data tools, enabling data analysts and scientists to extract valuable insights and enhance product offerings.

Working closely with database administrators to ensure efficient data storage and retrieval, leveraging indexing techniques and query optimization to improve performance.

# **Grokking Vietnam,** Ho Chi Minh— Lead Editor

MONTH 2017 - PRESENT

Leading Grokking Newsletter with more than 10,000 subscribers at

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: C++, Golang, Ruby

Data Engineering: Hadoop, Spark, Airflow

Databases: PostgreSQL, Cassandra

Tools: Prometheus, Grafana, Docker

Operating Systems: Unix/Linux

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor Of Computer Science at Ho Chi Minh University Of Science (2008–2012)

Master of Computer Science at HCMUS (2014)

Left in 2015. Leaving school early to take more time on the production cause life is short.

#### **LANGUAGES**

English

#### **OTHER**

I wrote a few technical blogs at

https://kipalog.com/users/Le PhongVu/mypage

#### newsletter.grokking.org.

Hosting Dijkstra, a publication for software engineers.

Developing and maintaining <a href="https://knowledge.grokking.org/">https://knowledge.grokking.org/</a>, a knowledge graph with more than 1000 articles.

## **VNG**, Ho Chi Minh— Backend Engineer

June 2018 - June 2019

Develop an image processing service with GPU (10000 rps) and a Recommended System for one of the largest music services in Vietnam.

# **Robert Bosch Vietnam,** Ho Chi Minh, Bangalore— *Software Engineer*

May 2016 - May 2018

Develop Speech Dialog System for Car Multimedia on Linux in India.

# **Personify**, Ho Chi Minh— Software Engineer

July 2014 - July 2015

Involved in the development of an application cross-platform for the 3D camera to connect people like they're there.

# NECVN, Ho Chi Minh, Tokyo — Software Engineer

Feb 2012 - April 2014

Participates in the development of applications in Windows, Android. Living more than 6 months in Tokyo to develop a cloud storage app.

Newsletter

https://newsletter.grokking. org/

Grokking Vietnam, a community to improve software engineer skill

https://www.grokking.org